Christian Sheen

csheen1725@gmail.com (786)832-1691 Miami, United States linkedin.com/in/csheen github.com/blksmth1725

Software Engineer: Front End Developer

Software engineer who creatively solves problems to deliver seamless user experiences. I strive to understand people, technology, and how they interact to build useful applications/features. The goal is to help others bring their ideas to life through technology, helping them reach customers and grow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Watch Systems LLC | Covington, LA | **06/2022 - Present** *Migration of legacy desktop applications to browser based applications*

- NCIC Security clearance.
- CJIS Security clearance.
- Frontend development of browser based application (OffenderWatch)
- API development for OffenderWatch
- Backend development working with NCIC application ties in our legacy application with NCIC DB as well as OffenderWatch
- Developmental work on our OffenderwatchMobile app that allows law enforcement to leverage our software out in the field from their phones

Junior Software Engineer | Pedra CRM LLC | Miami, FL | **06/2021 - 06/2022** Building CRM system for existing API

- Currently working on an iOS app with SwiftUI and Apollo as my Graphql client which provides the same functionality as the web application. (iOS)
- Designing of 10+ Views performing queries with persisted user authorization via session tokens. (iOS)
- Built payment feature on web application to process transactions and store users' payment information in a secure manner. (Web Next.js)
- Using Graphql to query and mutate data with over 20 query/mutation endpoints resulting in 3 features moving into production. (Web Next.js)
- Learning about business logic for CRMs to give said features an intuitive feel, allowing users to create, modify or delete at many instances within their pipeline. (Web Next.js)

Marketing + Operations Consultant | TD LUX | Miami, FL | **11/2018 - 04/2021** Led marketing, inventory, and operations projects

- Collaborated with the marketing team on 1-2 monthly campaigns to drive traffic towards our online platforms, resulting in 15% increase in online orders during COVID
- During Covid-19 peak: tasked with redesigning one of the locations. Created floor plans, renderings and designed new furniture. This resulted in 20% more square footage, which allowed us to provide guests with a safe dining experience.
- Created a process to track inventory and maintenance requirements across 6 restaurants allowing the business to efficiently repair or replace machines resulting in no down time.

Architectural Assistant | Archimia | Miami, FL | **07/2017 - 07/2018** *Created and modified architectural drawings*

- Authored 10 renders based on a residential project the firm was overseeing, resulting in the selection of materials/finishes which fit within the budget and satisfied clients aesthetic demands.
- Designing for over 800 hours in Revit. Contributed to 6 projects of which 4 I saw to completion.
- Sourced information from FBC & IBC to satisfy ADA, easement & egress, setback, FAR standards. Through proper implementation the business made fewer trips to the city for approval which improved delivery times.

EDUCATION + CERTIFICATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp 01/2019 - 01/2020

Bottega University, Utah (Remote)

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux, MongoDB

Certificate of completion 02/2021 - 03/2021

UDEMY, Node with React: Full stack Web Development

Certificate of completion 04/2021 - 05/2021

MERN stack front-back Web Development course

Architecture Associates in Art

Miami Dade College, Miami, FL Completed 70 credits hours toward a degree in Architectural Arts.

08/2012 - 08/2014

Courses:

- Adv. Design Theory
- Arch Structures
- Environmental Sys in Arch

LANGUAGES

English - Native or Bilingual Proficiency Spanish - Native or Bilingual Proficiency Italian - Limited Working Proficiency